<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kevin Zhang - the Sweeper Monk</title>
    <link>https://kevingzhang.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kevin Zhang - the Sweeper Monk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 13:37:29 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevingzhang.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Existing Centralized Trust Solution</title>
      <link>https://kevingzhang.github.io/posts/existing-centralzied-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 13:37:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingzhang.github.io/posts/existing-centralzied-trust/</guid>
      <description>Although we generally do not trust a machine in the middle of nowhere, in most cases we still use them, every day, every minute, every second. Cloud computing is one example. Nowadays most of the computing is happening in the data center of cloud computing providers, such as Amazon, Google, Microsoft, and others. We trust them because they are big names, and we trust them because we know they spend tons of resources to keep our data secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure your data at rest, in transmit, and more difficult, in use</title>
      <link>https://kevingzhang.github.io/posts/secure-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 22:12:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingzhang.github.io/posts/secure-data/</guid>
      <description>When we talking about secure our data, we actually mean three different stages of a data&#39;s life.
Data at rest: When data is sleeping in someone&#39;s hard drive. Data in transit: Data is transferred between two trusted domains. eg. from a database server to compute node, or from your browser to a server. Data in use: Data is calculated inside a machine (RAM and CPU) Data in transit problem has been resolved by cryptography, such as https have been widely used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First time blogging after six years</title>
      <link>https://kevingzhang.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 20:58:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingzhang.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I have not written any blog since 2013. Yes, I did write blogs, a long time ago. It was in the year 2005 when my daughter Emma was born. That was also the year my family and I immigrated to Canada. I wrote blogs almost every day about my everyday life as a new immigrant from an eastern country. There are too many things to be written to remember since not everyone has the chance to have the 2nd life - first 35 years living in the eastern world and the rest N (N =?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>